方法的规范有两部分。
Specification of a method has two parts.
有一个先决条件
There is the precondition, which is indicated
由这个关键词“需要”，和后置条件，表示
by this key word "requires", and the postcondition, indicated
通过关键字“影响”
by the keyword "affects."
先决条件是客户的义务，
Precondition is an obligation on the client,
方法的调用方。
the caller of the method.
它是调用方法的状态的条件。
It's a condition on the state in which the method is invoked.
通常它会讨论那个函数的参数，
Usually it talks about the arguments of that function,
但它可能会谈到
but it may talk about other things that are
在程序状态下。
in the state of the program.
后置条件是实施者的义务
Postcondition is an obligation on the implementer
方法。
of the method.
它说的是方法完成后必须是真的，
It says what has to be true after the method completes,
如果方法启动时保留了前提条件。
if the precondition held when the method started.
它的整体结构是一个逻辑含义。
The overall structure of this is a logical implication.
所以如果输入满足前提条件，
So if the input satisfies the precondition,
如果在调用方法时前提条件成立，
if the precondition holds when the method is called,
当方法完成时，后条件必须保持。
then the postcondition must hold when the method completes.
但如果前提条件不成立
But if the precondition didn't hold
当调用方法时，则实现
when the method was called, then the implementation
没有义务满足后条件。
is not obligated to satisfy the postcondition.
事实上，它可以做任何事情，包括
In fact, it's free to do anything, including
永远循环，或者抛出一个意外的异常，
looping forever, or throwing an exception that's unexpected,
返回一些任意的结果，使一些任意的
returning some arbitrary result, making some arbitrary
修改数据结构。
modification to a data structure.
如果输入不正确，所有下注都将被取消
All bets are off if the input doesn't
满足前提条件。
satisfy the precondition.
在Java中这看起来怎么样？
Now how does this look in Java?
嗯，有一些语言，一个很好的例子
Well, there are some languages, a good example
是埃菲尔铁塔吗，那实际上包括了先决条件
is Eiffel, that actually include preconditions
以及作为语言一部分的后置条件。
and post-conditions as part of the language.
它们由运行时系统强制执行，甚至
And they're enforced by the runtime system or even
由编译器编写。
by the compiler.
Java并没有走那么远，但是静态类型
Java doesn't go quite that far, but the static types
我们已经谈过的是有效的
that we've already talked about are effectively
方法的先决条件和后决条件的一部分。
part of the precondition and postcondition of a method.
你说的第一个参数
The fact that you have said that this first parameter
必须是int数组。
has to be an int array.
第二个参数必须是int，
The second parameter has to be an int,
它必须返回一个int——这些是约束
and it has to return an int-- these are constraints
论方法的输入与输出
on the input to the method and the output of the method
实际上是由编译器检查的。
that are actually checked by the compiler.
很好，因为那意味着
And that's good, because that means
检查和执行是自动进行的。
that checking and enforcement is happening automatically.
但合同的其余部分，
The rest of the contract, however,
剩下的部分，我们很难
the rest of the spec, the parts that we can't easily
以Java类型编写——我们必须写下来
write as Java types-- we have to write down instead
在方法前面的注释中。
in a comment, preceding the method.
一般来说，这取决于人类，程序员，
And generally that depends on human beings, programmers,
检查并保证。
to check it and guarantee it.
现在Java有了一个特殊的约定
Now Java has a particular convention
写这些评论。
for writing these kinds of comments.
它们被称为Javadoc注释。
They're called Javadoc comments.
在Javadoc的评论中，您
And in those Javadoc comments, you
使用这些at param子句描述参数
describe the parameters using these at param clauses
结果使用at return和at
and the results using at return and at
投掷——稍后我们将看到一些投掷的例子。
throws-- we'll see some examples of at throws later.
所以先决条件就是要求
So preconditions, that is requirements
在参数上，应该
that are put on the parameters, should
尽可能放入at param。
be put into the at param whenever possible.
所以我们注意到这里有一个要求条款
So we notice that we have this requires clause here
这给调用者设置了一个条件，一个先决条件
that puts a condition, a precondition on the caller
以确保这是满意的。
to make sure that that's satisfied.
我们把后置条件放入at-return和at-throws中。
And we put postconditions into the at return and at throws.
所以我们描述了我是什么
So we put a description of what that i is that it returns
它必须是
and the constraint that it has to be
一个元音出现的索引——我们把它放到光圈里。
an index where a vowel occurs-- we put that into the aperture.
现在Javadoc文档的优势
Now the advantage of Javadoc documentation
我们可以运行一个工具
is that we can run a tool that will automatically
提取这些评论并生成
extract these comments and produce
有吸引力的文件。
attractive documentation from it.
所以所有的标准Java API库文档
So all of the standard Java API library documentation
直接来自Javadoc对Java的评论
is coming directly out of Javadoc comments on the Java
库源。
library source.
有一个工具，事实上，
And there is a tool actually-- in fact,
该工具内置于Eclipse中——您
the tool is built into Eclipse-- that you
可以用来生成那些Javadoc HTML文件
can use to generate those Javadoc HTML files
从你自己的源代码。
from your own source code.
所以这就是为什么格式化您的规范是一个好主意
So that's why it's a good idea to format your specifications
像这样使用Javadoc语法。
using Javadoc syntax like this.
现在我们来谈谈一个特别有用的
Now let's talk about a particularly useful
隐含前提与后条件
implicit precondition and postcondition
我们要把所有的方法
that we're going to want to put basically on all the methods
我们在6005年使用的。
that we use in 6005.
这就是我们要排除空值。
And that is we want to exclude null.
所以我们先来谈谈空值。
So let's talk a bit about null first.
所以在Java中，任何引用，任何变量
So in Java, any reference, any variable
指向对象或数组的
that points to an object or to an array
允许接受特殊值null。
is allowed to take on the special value null.
当它为空时，基本上就是
And when it's null, that means basically it
什么都没指。
doesn't point to anything.
它不指向任何对象。
It doesn't point to any objects.
它不指向任何数组。
It doesn't point to any array.
不幸的是，这些空值--
Unfortunately, these null values--
它们在Java中的存在——在静态类型中是完整的
the existence of them in Java-- are whole in the static type
系统。
system.
一个简短的便条--整个
Now a quick side note-- this whole only
对象类型存在。
exists for object types.
像int和double这样的原语
So primitives like int and double-- these
不能为空。
can never be null.
会出现语法错误，而不是语义错误
You'll get a syntax error, rather a semantic error
如果您尝试将null用作int或double，则返回编译器。
from the compiler if you try to use null as an int or a double.
但是任何对象或数组引用
But any object or any array reference
可以将空值分配给它们。
can have null assigned to them.
编译器很乐意接受这段代码
And the compiler will happily accept this code
在编译时，但在运行时会出现错误。
at compile time, but you'll get errors at runtime.
因为，事实上，这个空值
Because, in fact, this null value
实际上不在字符串名称类型中。
is not actually in the string name type.
如果试图对name调用string方法，则
If you try to call a string method on name, which
碰巧有空值，你是
happens to have the null value, you're
会在运行时出错。
going to get an error at runtime.
它将产生一个空指针异常。
It's going to produce a null pointer exception.
类似地，如果尝试获取数组的长度
Similarly, if you try to take the length of an array
指向空的引用，你是
reference that points to null, you're
将获得空指针异常。
going to get a null pointer exception.
注意，因为空字符串与空字符串不同
Be careful because null is not the same as the empty string
或长度为0的数组。
or an array of length 0.
在空字符串和空数组上，
On empty strings and empty arrays,
您可以调用这些方法，并可以访问这些字段
you can call these methods, and you can access these fields
和财产。
and properties.
空数组的长度仅为0。
The length of an empty array is simply 0.
空字符串的长度仅为0。
The length of an empty string is simply 0.
您不会得到这些空指针异常。
You won't get these null pointer exceptions.
所以null实际上不是字符串。
So null is actually not a string.
实际上不是数组。
It's actually not an array.
这就是为什么不幸的是这是在Java中
And that's why it's unfortunate that this is in the Java
语言，因为它导致了代码
language, because it's leading to code
这是麻烦和不安全的，不安全的虫子。
that is troublesome and unsafe, not safe from bugs.
所以在6005中——事实上，在大多数优秀的Java编程中--
So in 6005-- in fact, in most good Java programming--
我们将隐式禁止空值
we're going to implicitly disallow null
作为对象或数组的可能参数返回值
as a possible parameter return value for an object or array
键入。
type.
所以每个接受objector数组参数的方法，
So every method that takes an objector array parameter,
或隐式返回objector数组类型
or returns an objector array type, implicitly
有一个前提条件说这些东西不能为空。
has a precondition that says those things can't be null.
并且隐式地有一个后置条件，它返回
And has implicitly has a postcondition that it's return
值不能为空。
value can't be null.
如果方法希望允许参数的空值
If a method wants to allow null values for a parameter
或者如果结果可能返回空值，
or if it might return a null value as a result,
它需要明确说明这一事实。
it needs to explicitly state that fact.
但如果你不说，那你就不允许。
But if you don't say it, then you're not allowing it.
一般来说，避免空值是个好主意。
In general, it's a good idea to avoid null.
实际上有Java的扩展
There are actually extensions to Java
允许你直接禁止空值
that allow you to forbid null directly
自动检查
and to have it checked automatically
在编译时或运行时。
at compile time or runtime.
下面是其中一个框架的示例。
Here's an example of one of those frameworks.
不幸的是，这不是标准Java中的。
That's not in standard Java, unfortunately.
但如果是的话会很好，因为那样的话
But it would be nice if it were, because then it
我们会进行静态检查
would be something that we'd have static checking
支持。
support for.
我还应该提到，这种避免无效
I should also mention that this avoidance of null
绝对不是6005的怪癖。
is by no means a quirk of 6005.
例如，谷歌有一个很长的讨论
For example, Google has a long discussion
在它的番石榴Java库中，这一点是一致的。
in its Guava Java libraries that agrees with this.
当你使用空的时候你会得到很多错误。
You get a lot of bugs when you use null.
最好快点失败，
And it's much better to fail fast,
正如我们在以前的课上讨论过的那样，
as we've talked about it in an earlier class,
而不是默默地接受和传播空值。
rather than silently accepting and propagating null.